<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike Yu</title>
    <link>https://mike-yu.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike Yu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mike-yu.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>mlbcal</title>
      <link>https://mike-yu.com/posts/mlbcal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mike-yu.com/posts/mlbcal/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy baseball and was glad when the lockout finally ended. Like many other people I soon found myself constantly refreshing the MLB website for the updated game schedule which is probably why this happened:
But what I actually wanted was the Mariners schedule as a CSV to make it easier to filter and sort to figure out which games I could go to this year. Last year I wrote a script to do just that for Mariners games and now seemed like a good time to add a few more features I wanted:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>trying out docopt</title>
      <link>https://mike-yu.com/posts/trying-out-docopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mike-yu.com/posts/trying-out-docopt/</guid>
      <description>trying out docopt    In my last post I created a very small command line interface (CLI) using argparse, which is a built in Python module. This time around I&amp;rsquo;m going to use the same code as before but instead of argparse I&amp;rsquo;ll use a third-party module calle docopt.
I got this idea from a great talk called From Python script to Open Source Project by Michał Karzyński. It has a lot of great content about putting together a fully-fledged open source Python project and I recommend watching the whole thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>argparse is cool</title>
      <link>https://mike-yu.com/posts/argparse-is-cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mike-yu.com/posts/argparse-is-cool/</guid>
      <description>argparse is cool    I need to copy files between S3 buckets on a regular basis for my job. The aws command line tool is great but I forget flags often&amp;hellip;and usually the same ones over and over. What if I made a custom version of aws s3 cp that was simpler and fit the majority of my copy usecases?
Well, here it is in 43 lines (with proper spacing) using argparse:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mike-yu.com/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mike-yu.com/reading/</guid>
      <description>2022     The Quiet Boy by Ben H. Winters Dark Matter by Blake Crouch Recursion by Blake Crouch The Midnight Library by Matt Haig Rock Paper Scissors by Alice Feeney  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Mike</title>
      <link>https://mike-yu.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mike-yu.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Favorites     Team: Mariners Bike manufacturer: Surly Text editor: Sublime Text Database engine: SQLite (maybe DuckDB soon) Python package: pandas Tech educator: Jake VanderPlas  Frequently used Python patterns    Flatten nested lists:
from itertools import chain flattened = list(chain.from_iterable([[1, 2, 3], [4, 5, 6], [7, 8, 9]])) csv.DictReader instead of csv.reader:
with open(&amp;#39;file.csv&amp;#39;) as f: csvreader = csv.DictReader(f) for row in csvreader: val = row[&amp;#39;col_name&amp;#39;] Turn a key/value list into dict of key -&amp;gt; list of values:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://mike-yu.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mike-yu.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>mlbcal    https://github.com/joeeoj/mlbcal
A pip-installable project that is a CLI wrapper around the MLB Stats API schedule endpoint.
Example usage:
$ mlbcal seattle --csv --nopre &amp;gt; mariners_schedule.csv
lahnman-to-duckdb    https://github.com/joeeoj/lahnman-to-duckdb
A wrapper around the baseballdatabank (aka Lahnman database) to convert the CSV files into a DuckDB database for faster, local analytics of baseball data. DuckDB is kind of like the OLAP version of SQLite.
Example queries against the database can be found here: examples.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
